Guide to the Stein and Day Publisher Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Stein and Day Publisher Records,
1963-1988
Stein and Day Publishers.
28.75 linear ft.(ca. 34,500 items in 68 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. 535 West 114th St., New York, NY, 10027.
4079521
History
Stein and Day Publishers was founded by Sol Stein and his wife Patricia Day in 1962 and remained in business until 1989. Primarily a trade book publisher of popular and literary fiction, biographies, and social history, it was also a publisher of military history, child and health care books.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, photographs and printed material. The editorial, publicity, and production files detail the publishing of some 450 titles, mostly from the 1970s and 1980s. Among the cataloged correspondents are: Woody Allen, Christy Brown, Claude Brown, Pearl S. Buck, William F. Buckley, Jr.; James T. Farrell, Leslie A. Fiedler, Jack Higgins, William Inge, Elia Kazan, Henry Miller, and J. B. Priestley. There are nineteen manuscripts, most with authorial or editorial corrections, as well as publicity photographs of Christy Brown, Claude Brown, Chester Himes, and Robert Oppenheimer, Jack Higgins et al.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Production Files
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Photographs
Subjects
Allen, Woody.; Kirkpatrick, Jeane J.; Buckley, William F. (William Frank), 1925-2008.; Cohen, William S.; Exon, J. James (John James), 1921-2005.; Glenn, John, 1921-; Heath, Edward.; Higgins, Jack, 1929-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Mailer, Norman.; Inge, William.; Logan, Joshua.; Martin, Malachi.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960.; Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1932-; Frost, David.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Brown, Christy, 1932-1981.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995.; Nunn, Sam.; Long, Russell.; Wallop, Malcolm.; Quayle, Dan, 1947-; Burns, James MacGregor.; Brown, Claude, 1937-; Shenker, Israel.; Morris, Desmond.; Hobson, Laura Keane Zametkin.; Buchwald, Art.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Hurst, Fannie, 1889-1968.; Priestley, J. B. (John Boynton), 1894-1984.; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993.; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992.; Kazan, Elia.; Fiedler, Leslie A.; Allen, Steve, 1921-2000.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998.; Publishers and publishing.; Photoprints; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-69. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
08/11/1989 M-89-11-08 Stein and Day Publishers Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letter is on microfilm.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Allen, Steve (Box 1)
  - Allen, Woody (Box 1)
  - Asimov, Isaac (Box 1)
  - Brown, Christy (Box 1)
  - Brown, Claude (Box 1)
  - Buchwald, Art (Box 1)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Box 1)
  - Buckley, William F,, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Burns, James MacGregor (Box 1)
  - Cohen, William S. (Box 1)
  - Exon, J. James (Box 1)
  - Farrell, James T. (Box 1)
  - Fiedler, Leslie A. (Box 1)
  - Frost, David (Box 1)
  - Glenn, John (Box 1)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Box 1)
  - Hayes, Helen (Box 1)
  - Heath, Edward (Box 1)
  - Hicks, Granville (Box 1)
  - Hobson, Laura Z. (Box 1)
  - Holloway, Stanley (Box 1)
  - Hurst, Fannie (Box 1)
  - Inge, William (Box 1)
  - Kazan, Elia (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, Edward M. (Box 1)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeane J. (Box 1)
  - Kissinger, Henry A. (Box 1)
  - Logan, Josh (Box 1)
  - Long, Russell (Box 1)
  - Macleish, Archibald (Box 1)
  - Mailer, Norman (Box 1)
  - Malden, Karl (Box 1)
  - Martin, Malachi B. (Box 1)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 1)
  - Morris, Desmond (Box 1)
  - Nunn, Sam (Box 1)
  - Patterson, Harry (Box 1)
  - Priestley, J. B. (Box 1)
  - Quale, Dan (Box 1)
  - Riegle, Donald W, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd (Box 1)
  - Shenker, Israel (Box 1)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase (Box 1)
  - Symms, Steve (Box 1)
  - Wallop, Malcolm (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Production Files
  - Abbott's New Card Games by Bob Abbott, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Acid Test by John Simon, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Actualizations Beyond EST by James M. Martin, l977 (Box 2)
  - Add Years to Your Life and Life to Your Years by Dr. Irene Gore, 1975 (Box 2)
  - After Reason by Arianna Stassinopoulos [Huffington], 1977, (3 folders ) (Box 2)
  - Afterplay by James Halpern and Mark A. Sherman, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Aircraft and Sea Power by Vice Admiral Sir Arthur Hezlet, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Alaska by Jon Gardey, 1976 (Box 3)
  - All the Drowned Sailors by Raymond B. Lech, 1984, (2 folders ) (Box 3)
  - The Almighty and the Almighty Dollar by Gordon L. Weil, 1979 (Box 3)
  - America America by Elia Kazan, 1962, (2 folders ) (Box 3)
  - America, I Love You by Harry Golden, 1975 (Box 3)
  - The Americans by David Frost, 1970 (Box 3)
  - America's Stonehenge Mystery Hill by Mark Feldman, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Anatomy of a Battle by Kenneth Macksey, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Anchorwoman by Al Morgan, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Andropov by Arnold Beichman and Mikhail Bernstam, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Animals of Africa by Bernhard Grzimek, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Anne Boleyn by Alison Plowden, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Answer to History by Mohammed Reza Pahlavi (Shah of Iran), 1980, (3 folders ) (Box 4)
  - Anything for a Quiet Life by Jack Hawkins, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Aperitifs and Liqueurs by Pamela Vandyke Price, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Arafat Is Next by Lionel Black (ie Dudley Barker, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Aretino's Dialogues tr. by Raymond Rosenthal, 1972 (Box 5)
  - The Arrangement by Elia Kazan, 1967, (4 folders ) (Box 5)
  - The Art of Psychological Warfare by Charles Roetter, 1974 (Box 6)
  - The Art of World Team Tennis by Greg Hoffman, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Aspects of Wagner by Bryan Magee, 1969 (Box 6)
  - The Assassins by Elia Kazan, 1972, (3 folders ) (Box 6)
  - Astrological Chart of the United States by Gar Osten, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Auto-Da-Fe by Elias Canetti, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Background Music by Christy Brown, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Backus Strikes Back by Jim Backus, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Ballet Cook Book by Tanaquil Le Clercq, 1967 (Box 7)
  - The Bank of America by Gordon L. Weil, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Barker, Dudley. General File. (Box 7)
  - The Bass Book by Homer Circle, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Battle of Arnhem by Cornelis Bauer, 1966 (Box 7)
  - The Battle of the Java Sea by David A. Thomas, 1974 (Box 7)
  - The Battle of Saratoga by Ruper Furneaux, 1983 (Box 7)
  - The Battle of the Torpedo Boats by Brian Cooper, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Beauty Makeover Guide by Judith Ross & Susan Acton, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Because It's There by Benjamin F. Schemmer, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Beichman, Arnold. General File. (Box 7)
  - Being Busted by Leslie Fiedler, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Better Wines for Less Money by Nathaniel Korshin, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Betrayal by Lucy Freeman and Julie Roy, 1976, (2 folders ) (Box 8)
  - Beyond Our Limits by Wendy Cooper and Dr. Tom Smith, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Billie's Blues by John Chilton, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Bobby Fisher vs the Rest of the World by Brad Darrach, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Body Shop by Corinne Browne, 1973 (Box 8)
  - The Bomb that Could Lip-Read by Donald Seaman, 1974 (Box 9)
  - The Book of Aphrodisiacs by Dr. Raymond Stark, 1980 (Box 9)
  - The Book of Before and After Dinner Drinking by Sheldon Wasserman, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Book of Tennis Lists, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Breakdown by N. S. Sutherland, 1976 (Box 9)
  - British Aircraft of World War II by John Frayn Turner, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Brown, Christy. General File. (Box 9)
  - The Burke Foundation by Anthony McCandless, 1987 (Box 9)
  - The Business of Living by Dr. Jack H. Grossman, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Bypassing Bypass by Elmer Cranton, 1984, (2 folders ) (Box 10)
  - Caruso by Stanley Jackson, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Casebook of a Psychic Detective by Dixie Yeterian, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Caught in the Act by William W. Pearce, 1978 (Box 10)
  - The Cavalry of World War II by Janus Piekalkiewicz, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Cedar Rat by Gary K. Everist, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Champaign Decoration on a Beer Budget by Doreen Roy, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Che Guevara by Daniel James, 1969, (2 folders ) (Box 11)
  - Chess Panorama by William Lombardy & David Daniels, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Childhood Illness by Jack G, Shiller, M,D. (Box 11)
  - Children of Ham by Claude Brown, 1976 (Box 11)
  - The Chinese Restaurant Cook Book by Barbara Myers, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Christopher Columbus by John Stewart Collis, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Classic Furniture Projects by A. W. Marlow, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Cleo by Mary Lutynes, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Cognac by Cyril Ray, 1973 (Box 12)
  - The Collected Essays of Leslie Fiedler by Leslie Fiedler, 1971 (Box 12)
  - A Collector's Guide to Paper Money by Yasha Beresiner, 1977 (Box 13)
  - The Comic by Brian Glanville, 1975 (Box 13)
  - The Complete All-in-the-Oven Cookbook by Dolores Riccio and Joan Bingham, 1982 (Box 13)
  - The Complete Bolivian Diaries of Che Guevara, 1968, (2 folders ) (Box 13)
  - The Complete Bonsai Handbook by Darlene Dunton, 1980 (Box 13)
  - The Complete Dictionary of Wood by Thomas Corkhill, 1980 (Box 13)
  - The Complete Dictionary of Television and Film by Lynne Naylor Ensign and Robyn Eileen Knapton, 1985 (Box 14)
  - The Complete International Appetizer Cookbook by Sonia Uvezian, 1981 (Box 14)
  - The Complete International Breakfast/Brunch Cookbook by Kay Shaw Nelson, 1981 (Box 14)
  - The Complete International One-Dish Meal Cookbook by Kay Shaw Nelson, 1980 (Box 14)
  - The Complete International Salad Book by Kay Shaw Nelson, 1978 (Box 14)
  - The Complete International Sandwich Book by Sonia Uvezian, 1981, (3 folders ) (Box 14)
  - The Complete International Soup Cookbook by Kay Shaw Nelson, 1980 (Box 15)
  - The Complete Manual of Wood Finishing by Frederick Oughton, 1982 (Box 15)
  - The Complete Pork Cookbook by Louise Sherman Schoon and Corrine Hardesty, 1977 (Box 15)
  - The Complete Rally Book by David Hebb, 1978 (Box 15)
  - The Complete Saussage Cookbook by Pamela Riddle, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Concord the Inside Story by Geoffrey Knight, 1976 (Box 15)
  - The Condensed World of the Reader's Digest by Samuel A. Schreiner, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Confessional by Jack Higgins, 1984, (2 folders ) (Box 16)
  - The Conquest of Chile by H. R. S. Pocock, 1968 (Box 16)
  - The Consumer's Guide to Banks by Gordon L. Weil, 1975 (Box 16)
  - The Consumer's Guide to Video Tape Recording by Boris Zmijewsky, 1979 (Box 16)
  - The Corporate Mentor by Karol White, 1982 (Box 16)
    [not published]
  - Cosmetic Surgery by William Brown, 1978 (Box 17)
  - Cosmic Influences on Human Behavior by Michel Gauquelin, 1975 (Box 17)
  - Country by Nick Tosches, 1977, (4 folders ) (Box 17)
  - Cozumel by E. Howard Hunt, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Cranko, John. Biographical information, 1973 (Box 17)
  - The Cretan Lover by Jack Higgins, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Crime and Punishment by Aryeh Neier, 1976 (Box 18)
  - The Crypto Man by Kenneth Royce, 1984 (Box 18)
  - A D & B on D & B by Isadore Barmash, 1978 (Box 18)
  - The Dark Side of History by Michael Edwardes, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Day of Judgment by Jack Higgins, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Deafness by David Wright, 1970 (Box 18)
  - The Defense Never Rests by F. Lee Bailey, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Descent of Woman by Elaine Morgan, 1972, (2 folders ) (Box 18)
  - Destination Peace by Gideon Rafael, 1981 (Box 19)
  - The Devil at Home by Oliver Lange, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Diary of a Harlem Schoolteacher by Jim Haskins, 1979 (Box 19)
  - Dictionary of Battles by Thomas Harbottle, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Dictionary of Catch Phrases by Eric Partridge, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Dictionary of Espionage by Henry S. A. Becket, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Dictionary of Symptoms by Dr. Joan Gomez, 1968 (Box 19)
  - The Difficult Child by A. J. Montanari & Arthur Henley, 1978 (Box 19)
  - Dillinger by Harry Patterson, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Disney's World by Leonard Mosley, 1985 (Box 20)
  - Disraeli in Love by Maurice Edelman, 1972 (Box 20)
  - Disraeli Rising by Maurice Edelman, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Dr. Kugler's Seven Keys to a Longer Life by Dr. Hans J. Kugler, 1978, (3 folders ) (Box 20)
  - Dr. Kugler's Seven Keys to a Longer Life by Dr. Hans J. Kugler, 1978, (2 folders ) (Box 21)
  - Dr. Shealy's Book of Occult Medicine by Dr. C. Norman Shealy, 1973 (Box 21)
  - The Doctor's Quick Weight Loss Diet by Samm Baker & Irwin Stillman, 1965 (Box 21)
  - Dog Training My Way by Barbara Woodhouse, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Dollars on Your Doorstep by Joseph Daffon, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Don't Ask Your Waiter by Pauline & Sheldon Wasserman, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Don't Change by Wendy Cooper, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Don't Get Perconel With a Chicken by H. Allen Smith, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Doors by Evan Hunter, 1976 (Box 22)
  - Down All The Days by Christy Brown, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Driven by Leon Mandel, 1977 (Box 22)
  - The Dying of the Light by Brian Glanville, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Eastside, Westside by Derek Lambert, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Easy Sleep by John J. Gnap, M.D., 1978 (Box 23)
  - The Eating Rich Cookbook by Leonard Louis Levinson, 1977 (Box 23)
  - Eclipse of Kings by Denis Judd, 1976 (Box 23)
  - Edith Cavell by Rowland Ryder, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Edward Kennedy: The Camelot Heritage by James MacGregor Burns, 1975 (Box 23)
  - The Eisenhower Deception by Clive Eagleton, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Electronics and Sea Power by Vice Admiral Sir Arthur Hezlet, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Elizabeth and Her Suitors by Alison Plowden, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Elizabeth R by Elizabeth Longford, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Elvis Calendar, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Encyclopedia of Dogs and Puppies by Barbara Woodhouse, 1978 (Box 23)
  - The Encyclopedia of the Occult, the Esoteric, and the Supernatural by Benjamin Walker, 1980 (Box 23)
  - England Ebbing by Jack Pitman, 1987 (Box 23)
  - The English by David Frost and Antony Jay, 1968, (2 folders ) (Box 23)
  - Enola Gay by Gordon Thomas and Max Morgan Witts, 1977, (2 folders ) (Box 24)
  - Escape by Dwight and Barbara Worker, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Esoteric Encyclopedia of External Knowledge by Vernon Howard, 1981 (Box 24)
  - European Theatre by Henry Popkin, 1979 (Box 24)
  - The Every Other Day Exercise Book by Fern Lebo, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Exocet by Jack Higgins, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Eye Book by Anne-Lise Gotzsche, 1975 (Box 24)
  - The Fabulous Life of Diego Rivera by Bertram D. Wolfe, 1963 (Box 25)
  - The Fail-Safe Fallacy by Sidney Hook, 1963, (2 folders ) (Box 25)
  - Falling Apart by Elaine Morgan, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Fame by Susan Margolis, 1977 (Box 25)
  - The Fantasy Game by Dr. Peter Dally, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Farmer's Law by Richard N. Farmer, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Femininity Game by Dr. Thomas Boslooper & Marcia Hayes, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Fiasco by John Deane Potter, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Fifth Class Mail by Jim Dwyer, 1978 (Box 26)
  - The Final Conclave by Malachi Martin, 1978, (2 folders ) (Box 26)
  - A Fistful of Heroes by Oliver Jacks, 1976 (Box 26)
  - The Flouride Question by Anne-Lise Gotzsche, 1974, (2 folders ) (Box 26)
  - Food in History by Reay Tannahill, 1973, (2 folders ) (Box 26)
  - Foods for Love by Robert Hendrickson, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Forbidden Cures by Steven Fredman, M.D. & Robert E. Burger, 1977 (Box 27)
  - Forbidden Universe by Leo Talamonti, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Fraud: The Amazing Career of Dr. Savundra by Jon Connell & Douglas Sutherland, 1979 (Box 27)
  - Friendship by Myron Brenton, 1974 (Box 27)
  - From a Gynecologist's Notebook by Sherwin A. Kaufman, M.D., 1974 (Box 27)
  - From Place to Place by Hannah Tillich (Box 27)
  - Frost, David. General File. (Box 27)
  - Funny People by Steve Allen, 1981 (Box 27)
  - G. K. Chesterton by Dudley Barker, 1973 (Box 28)
  - The Gaza Intercept by E. Howard Hunt, 1981 (Box 28)
  - Gestures by Desmond Morris et al, 1980 (Box 28)
  - Gideon's Force by William Vivian Butler, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Gideon's Law by William Vivian Butler, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Girodias, Maurice (Olympia Press). General File. (Box 28)
  - The Golden Express by Derek Lambert, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Great Medical Disasters by Dr. Richard Gordon, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Guernica by Gordon Thomas and Max Morgan Witts, 1975 (Box 28)
  - The Happy Person by Harold Greenwald and Elizabeth Rich, 1984 (Box 29)
  - The Harbor Mouse by Hannah Tillich, 1977 (Box 29)
  - The Hargrave Deception by E. Howard Hunt, 1980, (2 folders ) (Box 29)
  - He: An Irreverent Look at the American Male by Florence King, 1978 (Box 29)
  - Hitler in Vienna, 1907-1913 by J. Sydney Jones, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Hoffa: The Real Story by James R. Hoffa, 1975, (2 folders ) (Box 30)
  - Home Free by Chris Kazan, 1970 (Box 30)
  - How to Get Lucky by Max Gunther, 1985 (Box 30)
  - How To Protect Yourself Against Cops in California and Other (Box 30)
  - Strange Places by F. Lee Bailey, 1982 (Box 30)
  - I Have Come to Step Over Your Soul by Charles W. Sasser, 1986 (Box 30)
  - I Miss You When You're Here by Lee Leonard, 1976 (Box 30)
  - In Praise of Punishment by William Tucker, 1985 (Box 30)
  - Inside Story by Chapman Pincher (Box 30)
  - Instead of the Trees by J. B. Priestly, 1977 (Box 30)
  - An Irreverant and Thoroughly Incomplete Social History of Almost (Box 30)
  - Everything by Frank Muir, 1976 (Box 30)
  - J. P. Morgan by Stanley Jackson, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Japan Against the World: 1941-2041 by Russell Braddon, 1983 (Box 31)
  - The Jewish Mystique by Ernest van den Hoag, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Jewish Responses to Nazi Persecution by Isaiah Trunk, 1978, (3 folders ) (Box 31)
  - The Joey Adams Laugh Diary by Joey Adams, 1977 (Box 31)
  - The Judas Code by Derek Lambert, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Judenrat by Isahiah Trunk, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Kara Kush by Idries Shah, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Killing for Company by Brian Masters, 1986 (Box 32)
  - King, Florence. General File. (Box 32)
  - King David: King of the Beggars by Malachi Martin, 1978 (Box 32)
  - The Klan by Patsy Sims, 1978 (Box 32)
  - The Kremlin Conspiracy by E. Howard Hunt, 1985 (Box 32)
  - Lambert, Derek. General File., (2 folders ) (Box 33)
  - Landowska on Music ed. by Denise Restout, 1964, (2 folders ) (Box 33)
  - The Last Place On Earth by Harold T. P. Hayes, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Laughing All The Way by Barbara Hower, 1973 (Box 33)
  - Leading Ladies by Electra Clark, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Lenin Lives! by Gregory O'Brien, 1984 (Box 34)
  - Let Sleeping Dogs Die by Tim Heald, 1977 (Box 34)
  - Life After Marriage by Mary Ann Singleton, 1977 (Box 34)
  - A Lifetime's Reading by Philip Ward, 1983 (Box 34)
  - The Life and Legend of Sherlock Holmes by Terrance Dicks, 1975 (Box 34)
  - The Life and Times of Joe McCarthy by Thomas C. Reeves, 1981 (Box 34)
  - The Life and Times of Mohammed by Sir John Glubb, 1979 (Box 34)
  - Life Begins at Sixty by Bill Case, 1986 (Box 35)
  - A Life in Two Centuries by Bertram D. Wolfe, 1980 (Box 35)
  - Living in Step by Jeanette Lofas and Ruth Roosevelt, 1976 (Box 35)
  - Living is Loving by Inge and Sten Hegeler, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Living is Many Things by George Leo Robertson, 1977 (Box 35)
  - The Living Room by, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Living Safely in a Polluted World by Richard Mackarness, 1981 (Box 35)
  - Lloyd's of London by Anthony Brown, 1981 (Box 36)
  - Love and Death in the American Novel by Leslie Fiedler, 1965 (Box 36)
  - Love and Limerence by Dorothy Tennov, 1980 (Box 36)
  - Luciano's Luck by Jack Higgins, 1980 (Box 36)
  - Ma Bell by Richard Ottinger & Michael Kitzmiller, 1977 (Box 36)
  - Mad as Hell by Henry Miller, 1976 (Box 36)
  - Mafioso by Gaia Servadio, 1976 (Box 36)
  - Magna Carta by W. L. Warren, 1975 (Box 36)
  - The Major International Treaties by J. A. S. Grenville, 1974 (Box 36)
  - Making Ends Meet by Barbara Howar, 1974 (Box 36)
  - Man and the Beast Within by Benjamin Walker, 1974 (Box 37)
  - The Man from Devil's Island by Colin Richards, 1968 (Box 37)
  - Man is the Prey by James Clarke, 1969 (Box 37)
  - A Man of Principle by Dudley Barker, 1969 (Box 37)
  - The Man Who Had Power Over Women by Gordon M. Williams, 1967 (Box 37)
  - The Man Who Wanted Tomorrow by Brian Freemantle, 1975 (Box 37)
  - The Man Who Was Not Himself by John Creasy, 1976 (Box 37)
  - The Man Who Was Saturday by Derek Lambert, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Managing Your Doctor by Arthur Freese, 1974 (Box 37)
  - The Maple Harvest Cookbook by Diane Lewis, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Marconi: A Biography by W. P. Jolly, 1972 (Box 38)
  - Marine Sniper by Charles Henderson, 1986, (2 folders ) (Box 38)
  - Marriage With My Kingdom by Alison Plowden, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Martin by George A. Romero, 1977 (Box 38)
  - Mastering Herbalism by Paul Huson, 1974 (Box 39)
  - Mawson's Will by Lennard Bickel, 1977 (Box 39)
  - Mayday 747 by Alan Scott a.k.a. Reynolds Locke, 1974 (Box 39)
  - The Medusa Touch by Peter Van Greenaway, 1973 (Box 39)
  - Memos to Management by Frank A. Armstrong, 1974 (Box 39)
  - Mend It! by Maureen Goldsworthy, 1980 (Box 39)
  - Mensa by Victor Serebriakoff, 1986 (Box 39)
  - The Meredith Legacy by Sharon Salvato, 1974 (Box 39)
  - The Messengers Will Come No More by Leslie Fiedler, 1974 (Box 40)
  - MI5 by Nigel West, 1982 (Box 40)
  - Michel's Bird by Michel Legrand and George Mendoza, 1977 (Box 40)
  - Miracle of Deliverance by Stephen Harper, 1986 (Box 40)
  - The Monday Man by Ronny Pearlman, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Mopeds: The Complete Guide by Steve Pyle, 1978 (Box 40)
  - The Moscow Scene by Geoffrey Bocca, 1975 (Box 41)
  - The Mosley Receipt by Kenneth Royce, 1985 (Box 41)
  - The Most Wanted Man in America by John Clouser & Dave Fisher, 1975 (Box 41)
  - A Mouth Full of Sugar by Chris Kazan, 1971 (Box 41)
  - Moving Pictures by Budd Schulberg, 1981 (Box 41)
  - Muir, Frank. General File. (Box 42)
  - My England by Lydia Clarke Heston, 1984 (Box 42)
  - My Family by Grahame Hughes, 1977 (Box 42)
  - My Game by Ken Stabler with Lou Sahadi, 1978 (Box 42)
  - The Mystic Healers by Paris Flammonde, 1974 (Box 42)
  - Naked People by Abner Dean, 1964 (Box 42)
  - Napoleon and Talleyrand by Barbara Norman, 1976 (Box 43)
  - The New Apocrypha by John Sladek, 1973 (Box 43)
  - The New Eleusis by Robert Abbott, 1977 (Box 43)
  - The New FBI by Robert Pack, 1978 (Box 43)
  - The New Sexual Etiquette for Women ed. by Patricia Holt, 1977 (Box 43)
  - New York Intellectuals by Mark Krupnick, 1982 (Box 43)
  - The Nine Lives of Mickey Rooney by Arthur Marx, 1985 (Box 43)
  - No-Nonsense Government by Richard Sloma, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Non-Human Thought by Jacques Graven, 1967 (Box 44)
  - The Obituary Book by Alden Whitman, 1971 (Box 44)
  - An Occult Guide to South America by John Wilcock, 1976 (Box 44)
  - Off Camera by Leonard Probst, 1975 (Box 44)
  - Olivier ed. by Logan Gourlay, 1974 (Box 44)
  - The Oppenheimer Hearing by John Major, 1982 (Box 44)
  - Orient Express by Michael Barsley, 1967 (Box 44)
  - Other Senses, Other Worlds by Doris and David Jones, 1976 (Box 44)
  - Outdoor Power Equipment by Arthur Darack, 1977 (Box 45)
  - Particular Pleasures by J. B. Priestley, 1975 (Box 45)
  - A Partisan View by William Phillips, 1983 (Box 45)
  - Patterson, Harry. General information (Box 45)
  - Phobia Free by E. Ann Sutherland and Zalman Amit, 1977 (Box 45)
  - The Phoenicians Discovered America by Robert and Jennifer Marx, 1979 (Box 45)
  - Pinktoes by Chester Himes, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Poisioned Ivy by Benjamin Hart, 1984 (Box 46)
  - Portrait of Jesus? The Illustrated Story of the Shroud of Turin by Frank C. Tribbe, 1983, (3 folders ) (Box 46)
  - Priestley, J. B. General File. (Box 46)
  - The Retreat of Radiance by Ian Moffitt, 1985 (Box 46)
  - Richard Burton: The Erotic Search by Michael Hastings, 1977 (Box 46)
  - Rockefeller's Follies by William Rodgers, 1966 (Box 46)
  - The Rookies by Ed Walton, 1982 (Box 46)